so coming back to our Atomic
instructions we have seen that we can
have an atomic exchange where the
problem was that it keeps writing to the
lock bar even when it's not available
our test and right class of instructions
is trying to avoid that by testing the
memory location and only writing to it
if they find a zero there and we might
implement the log with a test and store
for example instruction we will
Implement a log by setting R1 to 1 then
testing lock while and storing R1 there
and the result we get from this testing
store let's say 0 in R1 means that the
lockvar was occupied in which case we
will just repeat this try this again and
again but the idea is that as long as
the lock is occupied this test and store
is only reading the lock variable it is
not writing to it this is good because
remember coherence if you keep writing
you keep invalidating all the other
copies so everybody that is waiting
keeps generating bus traffic because
they're all trying to write and US
invalidating each other in contrast the
test and store everybody that is waiting
while the lock is occupied simply gets
to share the lock variable
they're all having it in the shared
State and simply and simply iterating on
their cached copy once the lock has been
freed those shared copies are
invalidated because the unlock writes to
the lock variable at this point
everybody sees the new value and tries
to grab the lock so there is really only
communication on the lock when the log
becomes free until somebody acquires it
again so this test and write approach
solve the problem of continuously
writing to the log variable but doesn't
really solve the problem of this is a
really strange instruction it's neither
a store nor a load it would be ideal for
processor design if we could do
something that is very much like a load
and very much like a store yet behaves
this way and that brings us to the third
type of atomic instructions which are
really now two instructions they special
load and a special store that are
somehow linked together to create an
atomic instruction